Kai Wang

kaggle.com/kaiwang0112006 github.com/kaiwang0112006 cn.linkedin.com/in/kaiwang2009

Summary

I have experience in all process of data science, i.e., crawling, database, exploratory data analysis(EDA), modeling and data visualization. I'm interested in position as data scientist or data analyst.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Python, HTML5, CSS3, R, shell

Frameworks/Libraries: jQuery, D3.js, Django, Pyramid, Mako, sklearn, pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, ggplot2, networkx,

Database: mysql, mongoDB, neo4j.

Other: Git/GitHub, Bitbucket, Jira, Markdown, Letex.

Project Experience

Molecular Breeding Knowledge - mbkbase.org

Dec. 2014-present

- Built a website for genotype, phenotype and germplasm search and data display of rice. Pramid is used as framework.
- Designed complex search function as data exploring tools.
- Optimized function and MongoDB query that can speed up some page load from 1min to 3-4s.
- Designed many interactive data visualization pages to enhance user's exploring of data.

Prediction of Biological Activity of Acetylcholinesterase inhibitors -ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/ pubmed/22460031

May. 2009-May. 2011

- Collected a dataset containing 714 inhibitors.
- Built MLR and SVM models to predict the bio-activity of Acetylcholinesterase inhibitors.

Classification of Acetylcholinesterase inhibitors and decoys - ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/ 22263859

May. 2009-May. 2011

- Collected a dataset containing 714 inhibitors and 3892 decoys.
- Designed different pipeline for feature selection.
- Built several SVM classification models and the accuracy is up to 96.5%.

Work Experience

Institute of Genetics and Developmental Biology Chinese Academy of

Beijing, China | Jul. 2012-present

- Sciences Assistant Engineer
 - Performed genome and transcriptome assembly.
 - Developed database and website development & data visualization.

BioDuro Co., Ltd - Intern

Beijing, China | Jun. 2012-Jan. 2014

- Developed interface for molecular properties calculation, structure search and library enumeration based on Rgroup and reaction
- Assisted the update of compound database maintained in MDL® ISIS/Base

Education

Udacity - Data Analyst Nanodegree.

Jul. 2016

MongoDB, Inc - MongoDB for python Developers. (Training)

Feb. 2015

Beijing University of Chemical Technology - Chemical Engineering and Technology, M.S.

Jul. 2012

Beijing University of Chemical Technology - Bioengineering, B.S.

Jul.2009

Publication

- Dejun Li, Rizhong Zeng, Yan Li, Manman Zhao, Jinquan Chao, Yu Li, Kai Wang, Lihuang Zhu, Wei-Min Tian, Chengzhi Liang, Gene expression analysis and SNP/InDel discovery to investigate yield heterosis of two rubber tree F1 hybrids, Scientific Reports, 2016. 6:24984.
- Kai Wang, Xiaoying Hu, Zhi Wang, Aixia Yan*, Classification of Acetylcholinesterase Inhibitors and Decoys by a Support Vector Machine, Combinatorial Chemistry & High Throughput Screening, 2012. 15(6), 492-502.
- Aixia Yan*, Kai Wang, Quantitative structure and bioactivity relationship study on human acetylcholinesterase inhibitors, Bioorganic & Medicinal Chemistry Letters, 2012, 22(9), 3336-3342.
- Maolin Wang, Kai Wang, Aixia Yan*, Changyuan Yu*. Classification of HCV NS5B polymerase inhibitors using Support Vector Machine. Int.J.Mol.Sci, 2012, 13(4), 4033-4047.
- Aixia Yan*, Xianglei Nie, Kai Wang, Maolin Wang, Classification of Aurora Kinase inhibitors by Self-Organizing Map (SOM) and Support Vector Machine (SVM), Eur. J. Med. Chem, 2012(61), 73-83.
- Aixia Yan*, Yang Chong, Liyu Wang, Xiaoying Hu, Kai Wang, Prediction of Biological Activity of Aurora-A Kinase Inhibitors by Multilinear Regression Analysis and Support Vector Machine, Bioorganic & Medicinal Chemistry Letters, 2011,21(8), 2238-43.
- Kai Wang, Aixia Yan*, Introduction of several public databases for chemical activity on the Internet, Computers and Applied Chemistry, 2010,21(12): 1629-1632.